<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Valticus</title>
    <link>https://valticus.pro/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Valticus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://valticus.pro/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plans For The Nearest Future Of This Blog</title>
      <link>https://valticus.pro/posts/plans-for-the-nearest-future-of-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valticus.pro/posts/plans-for-the-nearest-future-of-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>Quick post on my plans for this blog.
Basically, I am planning to recommend you, the reader, what I use myself - be it a computer keyboard I use, a book I&amp;rsquo;ve read or a coffee brand I like.
What will be covered (the list is subject to change with time):
Programming Coding Books Hardware Software Merchandise Hope you will find my recommendations useful, or at the very least - entertaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Coding And Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://valticus.pro/posts/on-coding-and-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valticus.pro/posts/on-coding-and-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>AI, or Artificial Intelligence, is big at the moment, and to no surprise. AI can help humanity in many different areas, such as diagnosing an illness at an early stage, or assisting a driver with direction, or driving you to a desired destination.
While it is debatable whether or not we should trust AI to take over crucial areas of our lives (have you seen &amp;ldquo;Terminator?&amp;rdquo;), one area I found Artificial Intelligence to be particularly useful in is programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About Fonts (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://valticus.pro/posts/lets-talk-about-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valticus.pro/posts/lets-talk-about-fonts/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it - as developers we look at code 90% of our time we spend in front of the monitor. While there tons of fonts available for our favorite text editors, both free and paid, I have found one font in particular to be extremely enjoyable (and believe me - I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a few).
That is - JetBrains Mono, a free and open source font from the very same company that brought us tools like WebStorm and PyCharm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Have I Been Up To Recently?</title>
      <link>https://valticus.pro/posts/what-have-i-been-up-to-recently/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valticus.pro/posts/what-have-i-been-up-to-recently/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following my blog you might have noticed that I haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything in quite some time. &amp;ldquo;So, what&amp;rsquo;s up?&amp;rdquo;, you might ask.
Well, long story short - lots of things have happened March through May, 2021. Most of them unpleasant to say the least and personal, so I&amp;rsquo;d rather not disclose the details. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve also done a few things related to Information Technologies.
I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to Windows entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valticus | Programming, IT, and more.</title>
      <link>https://valticus.pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valticus.pro/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! You have taken a step closer to some interesting content. I hope you enjoy what I have to share.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
